Guide to the Brown Brothers Harriman Records 1696-1973, 1995 (bulk, 1820-1968) MS 78
New-York Historical Society
- Series X. Published Material (1801-1972), 6 Linear feet (5 boxes, 108 volumes)
  - "Manna-hatin": The story of New York. The Manhattan Company, 1929 (Offsite-box BBH-16, Volume 101)
  - Memorial address delivered in Grove Church, Hudson Co., N.J., December 16, 1877, in remembrance of Mr. James Brown deceased November 1, 1877. William V.V. Mabon, 1878 (Offsite-box BBH-16, Volume 102)
  - Memorial service at the unveiling of the tablet to the memory of Mr. James Brown, held October 10, 1886 at Grove Church, New Durham, N.J., 1887 (Offsite-box BBH-16, Volume 103)
  - Merchants and Bankers Almanac, 1869 (Offsite-box BBH-16, Volume 104)
  - Merchants and Bankers Almanac, 1870 (Offsite-box BBH-16, Volume 105)
  - Museums U.S.A. A history and guide. Herbert and Marjorie Katz, 1965 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 106)
  - The New York Stock Exchange. Francis L. Eames, 1894 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 107)
  - Notable New Yorkers of 1896-1899. Moses King, publisher (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 108)
  - Notes from Plymouth Pulpit: A collection of memorable passages from the discourses of Henry Ward Beecher. Augusta Moore, 1859 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 109)
  - The old merchants of New York City, vol I. Joseph A. Scoville, 1870 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 110)
  - The old merchants of New York, vol II. Joseph A. Scoville, 1870 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 111)
  - The old merchants of New York, vol III. Joseph A. Scoville, 1870 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 112)
  - The old merchants of New York, vol IV. Joseph A. Scoville, 1885 (Offsite-box BBH-17, Volume 113)
  - The old merchants of New York, vol V. Joseph A. Scoville, 1885 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 114)
  - Paddle box decorations of American sound steamboats. Alexander Crosby Brown [reprinted from The American Neptune, Vol III, No. 1, 1943], 1952 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 115)
  - Practical treatise on banking, volume I. J. W. Gilbart, 1849 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 116)
  - Practical treatise on banking, volume II. J. W. Gilbart, 1849 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 117)
  - Ramsay Lodge Association, 1948 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 118)
  - Rulers of America: A study of finance capital. Anna Rochester, 1936 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 119)
  - Seventy-five: A study of a generation in transition. Yale Daily News, 1953 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 120)
  - A short history of the United States. John Spencer Bassett, 1925 (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 121)
  - Society-list & club register for the season of 1886-7. (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 122)
  - The story of seventy-five years of Grove Reformed Church., [1918] (Offsite-box BBH-18, Volume 123)
  - Supplement to the yearbook of 1899 of the Society of the Sons of the Revolution in the State of New York. Members admitted July 1899-April 1903. (Offsite-box BBH-19, Volume 124)
  - Twenty-eight years in Wall Street. Henry Clews, 1888 (Offsite-box BBH-19, Volume 125)
  - Wall Street: A pictorial history. Leonard Louis Levinson, 1961 (Offsite-box BBH-19, Volume 126)
  - Walter S. Carter: Collector of young masters. Otto E. Koege, 1953 (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 127)
  - Who's who in commerce and industry, volume 8. A.N. Marquis Company, 1953 (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 128)
  - Will of James Brown, Esq. dated September 24, 1875, 1875 September 24 (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 129)
  - Women and children last: The tragic loss of the steamship Arctic. [reprinted from The American Neptune, vol XIV, No 4, October, 1954]. Alexander Crosby Brown (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 130)
  - World biography, 5th edition. Institute for Research in Biography, Inc., 1954 (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 131)
  - The Yes Men [privately bound for Morreau [sic] Brown], [1958] (Offsite-box BBH-20, Volume 132)